studyoptions.com 2019-05-29

# Privacy and Cookies Policy | Study Options

## General

References in this privacy policy to “we”, “our” and “us”, etc. are references to us, Study Options Limited, registered in England and Wales no. 05391269. We are committed to protecting your privacy and respecting the confidentiality of information which you provide when you visit our website at [www.studyoptions.com](https://www.studyoptions.com/). At the same time, we want to try to ensure that you obtain full value from our website and from the services which you may want to receive via our website.

We are registered as a data controller under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2018. You can see a copy of our entry on the Data Protection Register. We uphold the relevant data protection principles and process all personally identifiable information about you (“personal data”) in accordance with the GDPR and other relevant legislation. This privacy policy explains what information we may collect about you when you visit our website and how we may use it. This privacy policy explains what information we may collect about you when you visit our website and how we may use it. You should read this privacy policy in conjunction with our [website terms and conditions](https://www.studyoptions.com/terms-conditions "Terms & Conditions") of which this privacy policy forms a part. By agreeing to our terms of use, you are consenting to our processing of your personal data in accordance with this privacy policy. Any changes to this privacy policy will be posted on our web site and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

#### 1.       Introduction

1.1      We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors and our students.

1.2      This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors and our students; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

1.3      We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.

1.4      In this policy, "we", "us" and "our" refer to Study Options Ltd.  For more information about us, see Section 16.

#### 2.       How we use your personal data

2.1      In this Section 2 we have set out:

(a)       the general categories of personal data that we may process;

(b)      the purposes for which we may process personal data; and

(c)       the legal bases of the processing.

2.2      We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding your interest in studying in Australia or New Zealand. This data may include your full name, your email address, your phone number, your nationality, educational details and details about your study interests, and any further information you choose to provide to support your university application. The source of this data is one of our website contact forms or email. This data may be processed for the submission of your university application. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely providing you with information about your study options and/or submitting an application to universities on your behalf.

2.3      We may process data about your use of our website and services ("usage data"). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system (Google Analytics). This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

2.4      We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters ("notification data"). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is consent.

2.5      We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us ("correspondence data"). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.

2.6      We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

2.7      We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks.

2.8      In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

2.9      Please do not supply any other person's personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.

#### 3.       Providing your personal data to others

3.1      We may disclose your personal data to our university and college partners identified at <https://www.studyoptions.com/university-profiles> insofar as reasonably necessary for submitting your university application.

3.2      We may disclose your enquiry data to one or more of those selected third party suppliers of goods and services identified on our website for the purpose of enabling them to contact you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or services. Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party's use of your personal data.

3.3      In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

#### 4.       International transfers of your personal data

4.1      In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

4.2      The universities and colleges we represent are situated in Australia and New Zealand. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission.

4.3      You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

#### 5.       Retaining and deleting personal data

5.1      This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

5.2      Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

5.3      We will retain your personal data as follows:

(a)       Personal data submitted to us as part of a university application or enquiry will be retained for a minimum period of 3 years following application submission, and for a maximum period of 6 years following application submission.

5.4      In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on the following criteria:

(a)       the period of retention of personal data submitted to us as part of a university application or enquiry will be determined based on the duration of your studies in Australia or New Zealand.

5.5      Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

#### 6.       Security of personal data

6.1      We will take appropriate technical and organisational precautions to secure your personal data and to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal data.

6.2      We will store all your personal data on secure servers, personal computers and mobile devices, and in secure manual record-keeping systems.

6.3      Data relating to your enquiries that is sent from your web browser to our web server, or from our web server to your web browser, will be protected using encryption technology.

6.4      You acknowledge that the transmission of unencrypted (or inadequately encrypted) data over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

6.5      You should ensure that your password is not susceptible to being guessed, whether by a person or a computer program. You are responsible for keeping the password you use for accessing our website confidential and we will not ask you for your password (except when you log in to our website).

#### 7.       Amendments

7.1      We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

7.2      You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

7.3      We may notify you of significant changes to this policy by email.

#### 8.       Your rights

8.1      In this Section 9, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

8.2      Your principal rights under data protection law are:

(a)       the right to access;

(b)      the right to rectification;

(c)       the right to erasure;

(d)      the right to restrict processing;

(e)       the right to object to processing;

(f)       the right to data portability;

(g)      the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and

(h)      the right to withdraw consent.

8.3      You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can request your personal data by submitting a request via our website.

8.4      You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

8.5      In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

8.6      In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

8.7      You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

8.8      You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

8.9      You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

8.10    To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

(a)       consent; or

(b)      that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

8.11    If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

8.12    To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

8.13    You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us in addition to the other methods specified in this Section 8.

#### 9.       Third party websites

9.1      Our website includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.

9.2      We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of third parties.

#### 10.      Personal data of children

10.1    Our website and services are targeted at persons over the age of 16.

10.2    If we have reason to believe that we hold personal data of a person under that age in our databases, we will delete that personal data.

#### 11.      Updating information

11.1    Please let us know if the personal information that we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

#### 12.      About cookies

12.1    A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

12.2    Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

12.3    Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

#### 13.      Cookies that we use

13.1    We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a)       authentication - we use cookies [to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;

(b)      security - we use cookies [as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally;

(c)       analysis - we use cookies [to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services; and

(d)      cookie consent - we use cookies [to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally.

#### 14.      Cookies used by our service providers

14.1    Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

14.2    We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

14.3    We use Share This to provide social sharing links on our pages. This service uses cookies. You can view the privacy policy of this service provider at <https://www.sharethis.com/privacy/>.

#### 15.      Managing cookies

15.1    Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a)       <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b)      <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c)       <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d)      <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e)       <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f)       <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

15.2    Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

15.3    If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

#### 16.      Our details

16.1    This website is owned and operated by Study Options Ltd.

16.2    We are registered in England and Wales under registration number 5391269, and our registered office is at 201 Haverstock Hill, London, NW3 4QG.

16.3    Our principal place of business is at 83 Alma Road, Clifton, Bristol, BS8 2DP.

16.4    You can contact us:

(a)       by post, to the postal address given above;

(b)      using our website contact form;

(c)       by telephone, on the contact number published on our website; or

(d)      by email, using [mail@studyoptions.com](mailto:mail@studyoptions.com).

#### 17.      Data protection registration

17.1    We are registered as a data controller with the UK Information Commissioner's Office.

#### 18.      Representative within the European Union

18.1    Our representative within the European Union with respect to our obligations under data protection law is Stefan Watts and you can contact our representative at 83 Alma Road, Clifton, Bristol, BS8 2DP, by phone on 0117 911 5610 or by emailing [mail@studyoptions.com](mailto:mail@studyoptions.com).

#### 19.      Data protection officer

19.1    Our data protection officer's contact details are: Stefan Watts, 83 Alma Road, Clifton, Bristol, BS8 2DP. Phone: 0117 911 5610. Email: [mail@studyoptions.com](mailto:mail@studyoptions.com).
